Guide to the Academy of Political Science letters,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Academy of Political Science letters,
1923-1970.
Academy of Political Science (U.S.)
0.5 linear ft. (19 items in 1 document box).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
MS#0006
4078391
History
The Academy of Political Science (APS), founded in 1880, promotes objective, scholarly analyses of political, social, and economic issues. Through its conferences and publications APS provides analysis and insight into both domestic and foreign policy issues.
The Academy was established in 1880 as an adjunct to the activities of Columbia University's Law School and newly created Graduate School of Political Science. Senior members of its faculty and graduate scholars saw the need for a companion institution to serve as a link between the academic world of political science and the larger world of practical politics and government.
Although membership was initially limited to affiliates of Columbia, the Academy's relationship with the University has always been informal, limited to an agreement by Columbia's trustees to allow use of some of its buildings for Academy meetings and functions.
In 1896 membership was extended to other political scientists and to students of politics in universities and colleges throughout the country. In 1910 the Academy was formally incorporated as a non-for-profit institution in New York State. A constitution and by-laws were adopted and, in keeping with its growing influence and the developing interest of the general public, the Academy opened membership privileges to all who shared its interests and would pay its nominal dues.
Due to its well established effort to provide analysis on domestic and foreign affairs, the Academy enjoys a special prestige among the many institutions, committees and think tanks devoted to the exploration and exposition of public policy. More important than mere longevity are the depth and breadth of intellectual competence that the Academy's members bring to their chosen fields. Furthermore, there is the assurance that all publications of the Academy are not shaped by ideological or partisan considerations.
Scope and Content
Letters from Dean Rusk, Jean Monnet, Lyndon Johnson, Dwight Eisenhower, David Ben-Gurion, Earl Warren, and others concerning their being made honorary members of the Academy of Political Science.
Arrangement
Cataloged in full.
Subjects
Academy of Political Science in the City of New York.; Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1904-1971.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986.; Malik, Charles Habib, 1906-1987.; McCloy, John J. (John Jay), 1895-1989.; Rusk, Dean, 1909-1994.; Lasker, Mary.; Monnet, Jean, 1888-1979.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Ben-Gurion, David, 1886-1973.; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937.; Smith, Margaret Chase, 1897-1995.; Warren, Earl, 1891-1974.; Political science.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
1970 Letters Academy of Political Science Gift
Gift of the Academy, 1970.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Ben-Gurion, David To: Robert H. Connery. Sdeh Boker, Israel 1970-1971 (2 autograph letters signed) (Box 1)
  - Bunche, Ralph J. To: Robert H. Connery. New York 5 March 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Dewey, Thomas Edmund To: Robert H. Connery. New York 1 April 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. To: Lewis. W. Douglas. [n.p.] 28 February 1948 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Milton, Dwight S. To: Robert H. Connery. Baltimore, Md. 2 March 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Harriman, William Averell To: Robert H. Connery. Washington D.C. 11 March 1970 ( 1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. To: Robert H. Connery. Austin, Texas 6 November and 9 December 1969 (2 typed letters signed) (Box 1)
  - Lasker, Mary To: Robert H. Connery. New York 10 March 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - McCloy, John Jay To: Robert H. Connery. New York 8 February 1968 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Malik, Charles To: Robert H. Connery. New York 31 March 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Martin, Paul To: Robert H. Connery. New York 10 March 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Martin, Paul To: Robert H. Connery. Canada 10 March 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Monnet, Jean To: Robert H. Connery. Paris, France 9 March 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Parson, Lester Bowles To: Robert H. Connery. Ottawa, Canada 7 November 1969 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Romulo, Carlos P. To: Robert H. Connery. Manila, Philippines 14 April 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Root, Elihu To: Parker Thomas Moon. New York 7 March 1923 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Rusk, Dean To: Robert H. Connery. New York 6 November 1969 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Smith, Margaret Chase To: Robert H. Connery. Washington D.C. 5 March 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)
  - Warren, Earl To: Robert H. Connery. Washington D.C. 28 January 1970 (1 page, typed letter signed) (Box 1)